<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Laskauxian Diary</title>
    <atom:link href="/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <description></description>
    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 13:27:58 -0400</pubDate>
    
      <item>
        <title>In the Name of Liberté&amp;colon;&amp;nbsp; II. Rights of Citizens</title>
        <link>/2020/03/29/revolution-rights.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/03/29/revolution-rights.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Reconciliation of 17 July—&lt;em&gt;Grande Peur&lt;/em&gt;—August Decrees—&lt;em&gt;Declaration of the Rights of Man and of the Citizen&lt;/em&gt;—Veto debate—&lt;em&gt;Orgie des gardes du corps&lt;/em&gt;—March on Versailles/October Days—Mirabeau’s secret letters—&lt;em&gt;Fête de la Fédération&lt;/em&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;17-july-1789-reconciliation&quot;&gt;17 July 1789: Reconciliation&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Early on 17 July the Count d’Artois left Versailles for the north-east frontier, to be followed over subsequent weeks by many of the courtiers . . . And later the same day the king made his way, escorted only by a handful of deputies, to the Hôtel de Ville of Paris to confirm that the troops were withdrawing and announce that Necker had been recalled. He also confirmed the nomination of Bailly as mayor of Paris (a new title) and Lafayette as commander of the new citizens’ militia, now being called the National Guard. It was said that 150,000 armed citizens were on the streets that day, all wearing cockades in red and blue, the colours both of the city and the Duke d’Orlaéns. Later in the month Lafayette would splice them with Bourbon white for the uniform of his National Guardsmen, and so the patriotic tricolour was born. The king accepted a cockade and stuck it in his hat on arrival at the Hôtel de Ville; and then, for the first time, people began to cheer him.   [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Together with comte d’Artois, the family of duchesse de Polignac left France, who never reunites with Marie-Antoinette thereafter. Louis’s visit to Paris on 17 July begins with a ceremonial key conferment at the Barrière de Chaillot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;« J’apporte à votre Majesté les clés de sa bonne ville de Paris : ce sont les mêmes qui ont été présentées à Henri IV ; il avait reconquis son peuple, ici le peuple a reconquis son roi. »&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[“I bring your Majesty the keys to his good city of Paris: these are the same ones that were presented to Henri IV; he had won back his people; here the people have won back their king.”]&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Bailly, &lt;em&gt;Mémoires d'un témoin de la Révolution&lt;/em&gt;, Tome 2&lt;sup&gt;e&lt;/sup&gt; (1804)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;20-july6-august-1789-grande-peur&quot;&gt;20 July–6 August 1789: &lt;em&gt;Grande Peur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fear of aristocratic revenge replaced such hope as news of the Bastille arrived . . . Hope, fear, and hunger made the countryside a tinder-box ignited by imagined sightings of ‘brigands’. Panics spread from five separate sparks as bushfires of angry rumours, spreading from village to village at several kilometres an hour, engulfed every region but Brittany and the east. When noble revenge failed to materialize, village militias instead turned their weapons on the seigneurial system itself, compelling seigneurs or their agents to hand over feudal registers to be burned on the village square. This extraordinary revolt came to be known as the ‘Great Fear’.  [PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;4-august-1789-abolition-of-feudalism&quot;&gt;4 August 1789: Abolition of feudalism&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the night of 4 August, in an extraordinary atmosphere of panic, self-sacrifice and exhilaration, a series of nobles mounted the rostrum of the Assembly to respond to the Great Fear by renouncing their privileges and abolishing feudal dues.  [PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This reenactment of the &lt;em&gt;Nuit du 4 août 1789&lt;/em&gt; freatures five orators: &lt;strong&gt;Isaac René Guy le Chapelier&lt;/strong&gt; (Bernard Spiegel),
&lt;strong&gt;Louis Marc Antoine, vicomte de Noailles&lt;/strong&gt; (Georges Fricker),
&lt;strong&gt;Alexandre François Marie, vicomte de Beauharnais&lt;/strong&gt; (Frédéric Rostand),
duc de la Rochefoucauld-Liancourt (Yves-Marie Maurin), and
&lt;strong&gt;Anne-Louis-Henri de La Fare, évêque de Nancy&lt;/strong&gt; (Jacques Plée).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M. le Président&lt;/strong&gt; (M. Chapelier) &lt;br /&gt;
a proposé ensuite de reprendre la discussion sur la déclaration de droits, dont il a été présenté plusieurs plans pour être mis en tête de la Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Séance du soir.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M. le vicomte de Noailles&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
. . . je propose : 1° . . . que l’impôt sera payé par tous les individus du royaume, dans la proportion de leurs revenus ; 2° Que toutes les charges publiques seront à l’avenir supportées égaleineut par tous ; 3° Que tous les droits féodaux seront racheta. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M. le vicomte de Beauharnais&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
propose l’égalité des peines sur toutes les classes des citoyens, et leur admissibilité dans tous les emplois ecclésiastiques, civils et militaires.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M. de Lafare&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
évêque de Nancy . . . Je viens exprimer, au nom du clergé, le vœu de la justice, de la religion et de l’humanité ; je demande le rachat pour les fonds ecclésiastiques, et je demande que le rachat ne tourne pas au profit du seigneur ecclésiastique, mais qu’il en soit fait des placements utiles pour l’indigence.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[AP, Tuesday 4 August 1789]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The resolutions were proclaimed as the &lt;em&gt;Décrets des 4, 6, 7, 8 et 11 août 1789&lt;/em&gt;, or the August Decrees. Slavery was not abolished throughout France until 1794. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;26-august-1789-declaration-of-the-rights-of-man-and-of-the-citizen&quot;&gt;26 August 1789: &lt;em&gt;Declaration of the Rights of Man and of the Citizen&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last article of the &lt;em&gt;Déclaration des droits de l’homme et du citoyen de 1789&lt;/em&gt; was voted and adopted by the Assemblée nationale constituante (National Constituent Assembly) on 26 August. In the film, excerpts of its original text are read to the Assembly by La Fayette, who prepared its first draft on 11 July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Les Représentants du Peuple Français, constitués en Assemblée Nationale, considérant que l’ignorance, l’oubli ou le mépris des droits de l’Homme sont les seules causes des malheurs publics et de la corruption des Gouvernements, ont résolu d’exposer, dans une Déclaration solennelle, les droits naturels, inaliénables et sacrés de l’Homme, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 1&lt;sup&gt;er&lt;/sup&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;  Les hommes naissent et demeurent libres et égaux en droits. Les distinctions sociales ne peuvent être fondées que sur l’utilité commune.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 2.&lt;/strong&gt;  . . . Ces droits sont la liberté, la propriété, la sûreté, et la résistance à l’oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 3.&lt;/strong&gt;  Le principe de toute Souveraineté réside essentiellement dans la Nation. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 5.&lt;/strong&gt;  La Loi n’a le droit de défendre que les actions nuisibles à la Société. Tout ce qui n’est pas défendu par la Loi ne peut être empêché, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 6.&lt;/strong&gt;  La Loi est l’expression de la volonté générale. . . . Tous les Citoyens étant égaux à ses yeux sont également admissibles à toutes dignités, places et emplois publics, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 7.&lt;/strong&gt;  Nul homme ne peut être accusé, arrêté ni détenu que dans les cas déterminés par la Loi, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 9.&lt;/strong&gt;  Tout homme étant présumé innocent jusqu’à ce qu’il ait été déclaré coupable, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 10.&lt;/strong&gt;  Nul ne doit être inquiété pour ses opinions, même religieuses, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 11.&lt;/strong&gt;  La libre communication des pensées et des opinions est un des droits les plus précieux de l’Homme : tout Citoyen peut donc parler, écrire, imprimer librement, sauf à répondre de l’abus de cette liberté dans les cas déterminés par la Loi.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 12.&lt;/strong&gt;  La garantie des droits de l’Homme et du Citoyen nécessite une force publique : cette force est donc instituée pour l’avantage de tous, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 17.&lt;/strong&gt;  La propriété étant un droit inviolable et sacré, nul ne peut en être privé, si ce n’est lorsque la nécessité publique, légalement constatée, l’exige évidemment, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The standard English translation is the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The representatives of the French people, organized as a National Assembly, believing that the ignorance, neglect, or contempt of the rights of man are the sole cause of public calamities and of the corruption of governments, have determined to set forth in a solemn declaration the natural, unalienable, and sacred rights of man, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 1.&lt;/strong&gt;  Men are born and remain free and equal in rights. Social distinctions may be founded only upon the general good.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 2.&lt;/strong&gt;  . . . These rights are liberty, property, security, and resistance to oppression.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 3.&lt;/strong&gt;  The principle of all sovereignty resides essentially in the nation. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 5.&lt;/strong&gt;  Law can only prohibit such actions as are hurtful to society. Nothing may be prevented which is not forbidden by law, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 6.&lt;/strong&gt;  Law is the expression of the general will. . . . All citizens, being equal in the eyes of the law, are equally eligible to all dignities and to all public positions and occupations, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 7.&lt;/strong&gt;  No person shall be accused, arrested, or imprisoned except in the cases and according to the forms prescribed by law. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 9.&lt;/strong&gt;  All persons are held innocent until they shall have been declared guilty, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 10.&lt;/strong&gt;  No one shall be disquieted on account of his opinions, including his religious views, . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 11.&lt;/strong&gt;  The free communication of ideas and opinions is one of the most precious of the rights of man. Every citizen may, accordingly, speak, write, and print with freedom, but shall be responsible for such abuses of this freedom as shall be defined by law.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 12.&lt;/strong&gt;  The security of the rights of man and of the citizen requires public military forces. These forces are, therefore, established for the good of all . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Article 17.&lt;/strong&gt;  Property is an inviolable and sacred right. No one shall be deprived thereof except where public necessity, legally determined, shall clearly demand it, . . .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Article 11 on freedom of the press was adopted on 24 August. Two impactful revolutionary newspapers were launched shortly in the following fall: Jean-Paul Marat’s &lt;em&gt;L’Ami du peuple&lt;/em&gt; (originally &lt;em&gt;Le Publiciste parisien&lt;/em&gt;) and Camille Desmoulins’s &lt;em&gt;Révolutions de France et de Brabant&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;september-1789-veto-debate&quot;&gt;September 1789: Veto debate&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Admirers of the checks and balances of the British constitution dominated the Assembly’s constitutional committee, and they believed that the king should have the same powers of veto as the British monarch. Led by Mounier, Malouet, and a handful of rich and eloquent metropolitan nobles like Lally-Tollendal and Clermont-Tonnerre, and energetically supported by Mirabeau, these &lt;em&gt;monarchiens&lt;/em&gt; (as their opponents dubbed them) spent the first two weeks of September trying to hustle the Assembly into accepting their programme. . . . But only a handful of deputies, such as Sieyès and the prolix but still uninfluential Robespierre, believed that once the National Assembly had pronounced the monarch should have no veto at all. Most, including patriotic leaders like Barnave, Duport, and the noble Lameth brothers, were attracted to the idea of a temporary or ‘suspensive’ veto; and when Necker let it be known that this was also the king’s preference, they detected a hint that the August decrees would be sanctioned if it was carried. Consequently the suspensive veto passed overwhelmingly (673 votes to 352) on 15 September.  [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This tortuous deliberation started as early as in June on the Estates-General:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;M. le comte de Mirabeau&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . . Et moi, Messieurs, je crois le veto du Roi tellement nécessaire que l’aimerais mieux vivre à Constantinople qu’en France, s’il ne l’avait pas . . . je ne connaîtrais rien de plus terrible que l’aristocratie souveraine de six cents personnes qui demain pourraient se rendre inamovibles, après-demain héréditaires, et finiraient, comme les aristocrates de tous les pays du monde, par toute envahir.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[Sirs, I think the King’s veto so essential that I had rather live in Constantinople than in France if he did not have it. . . . I know nothing more terrible than the sovereignty of six hundred persons, who tomorrow will constitute themselves a permanent body, the next day hereditary, and will end by usurping everything.]&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[AP, Tuesday 16 June 1789]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the film, Mirabeau’s view is reflected through the witty dinner chat with Camille Desmoulins, whose friendship begin in the summer of 1789:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was during these summer months, immediately after the fall of the Bastille, that the friendship began between Camille Desmoulins and Gabriel-Honoré de Riquetti, Comte de Mirabeau. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;It would appear that Camille first brought himself to the notice of the great Revolutionary Tribune as early as the spring of 1789, by asking for a post on the staff of the paper which Mirabeau edited.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Although there is no evidence that Camille ever contributed personally to Mirabeau’s paper, it is probable that the great man foresaw that the journalist might be useful to him in the future. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;He made much of Camille, he invited him to his house, gave him such dinners as the young fellow had never probably conceived as possible, showed him life in more senses of the word than one.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Camille was absolutely dazzled, and small wonder. Mirabeau was rapidly becoming the most prominent man of his day, and he was as great in fascination as in all else. Where he cared sufficiently to exert his power—and there is little doubt that he cared for Camille—he could be irresistible.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Violet Methley, &lt;em&gt;Camille Desmoulins: A Biography&lt;/em&gt; (1914)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The papers Desmoulins drafts and Mirabeau signs are probably for Mirabeau’s &lt;em&gt;Courrier de Provence&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1-october-1789-orgie-des-gardes-du-corps&quot;&gt;1 October 1789: &lt;em&gt;Orgie des gardes du corps&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was the first time the Assembly had flouted popular sentiment, for in Paris and many of the provinces it was clear that any form of veto aroused deep mistrust. . . . Such paranoid attitudes were compounded by persistent economic difficulties in the capital. After falling somewhat in late July and August, the price of bread began to climb again and supplies became irregular. . . . Guards were placed on bakers’ shops, and Lafayette and his militia found themselves hard pressed to contain all the incidents that occurred.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Parallels with the situation early in July escaped no one. . . . Alarmed at persistent rumours of being taken by force to Paris, on 14 September the king summoned the notoriously well-disciplined Flanders Regiment from the north-east frontier to Versailles. . . . . Encouraged by the security it seemed to promise, the king broke silence on the August decrees. On 18 September, in a long letter drafted by Necker, he explained that he was prepared to accept some parts of the 11 August decree but not others. . . . Then on 4 October he voiced reservations about the Declaration of Rights. By now, however, Paris was alive with rumours about a reception given by the King’s bodyguard on 1 October to welcome the Flanders Regiment. After many noisy toasts had been drunk, and none to the nation, the national cockade was said to have been trampled as the air rang with unpatriotic slogans.   [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The banquet in honor of the Régiment de Flandre (in white uniforms) is hosted in the Opéra royal du château de Versailles by the Garde du corps du roi (in blue and red). The orchestra are playing “Ô Richard, ô mon roi !,” an aria from André Grétry’s opéra comique &lt;em&gt;Richard Cœur-de-Lion&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;During the banquet, toasts to the king and royal family were drunk with enthusiasm, while the nation was omitted or rejected. . . . Suddenly the king was announced; he entered attired in a hunting dress, the queen leaning on his arm, and carrying the dauphin. Shouts of affection and devotion arose on every side. . . . while cockades were distributed; the tri-coloured cockade, it is said, was trampled on . . .   [FAM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;56-october-1789-womens-march-on-versailles&quot;&gt;5–6 October 1789: Women’s March on Versailles&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Banquets themselves seemed unpatriotic when bread was so scarce, and by 4 October all Paris believed that counter-revolutionary orgies at Versailles were the prelude to a new attempt to starve the capital. The next morning, several districts of the city were awakened by the ringing of the tocsin from church bell-towers, recognized ever since the days of July as a call to arms. Crowds of women began to assemble at markets, from where they marched to the Hôtel de Ville. After surging through the building to impress the city authorities with their determination, late in the morning they set off for Versailles dragging cannon and brandishing whatever makeshift weapons they could lay hands on, recruiting newcomers as they went along. Perhaps 7,000 of them reached Versailles early in the evening and invaded the National Assembly, calling for bread and punishment for those who had insulted the national cockade. The unprotected deputies had no alternative but to welcome them with mollifying speeches. They were visibly relieved when a deputation went on to confront the king.   [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Danton’s involvement in this insurrection can be found in Hilaire Belloc’s &lt;em&gt;Danton: A Study&lt;/em&gt; (1899):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the morning of Sunday, a day when there was leisure to read, the walls were placarded with the manifesto of the Cordeliers. It demanded an insurrection, and was signed with Danton’s name. On Monday morning they rang the tocsin at the belfry of the convent, and the battalion of the district was drawn up and armed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading the Women’s March is Stanislas-Marie Maillard (Patrick Tessari), the same mod captain at the Bastille. The delegation is headed by &lt;strong&gt;Jean-Joseph Mounier&lt;/strong&gt; (Jacques Penot), then president of the National Constituent Assembly, and includes &lt;strong&gt;Louison Chabry&lt;/strong&gt; (Marion Grimault), a flowergirl who briefly appears at the beginning of the Café de Foy scene on 12 July.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mounier and the deputation, of which he was the head, six deputies of the Assembly and six women, who were joined by six other women, made their way with difficulty through the crowd in the Palace d’Armes, which had become a sea of pikes and muskets. The king received them with his customary graciousness.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“Sire, we want bread,” said Louison Chabry, a pretty flower-girl of seventeen from the Palais-Royal, as speaker for the women.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“I will order all the bread in Versailles to be collected and given to you,” declared the king.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Louison, overcome by emotion at the king’s goodness, fainted. When she recovered her senses, she begged to kiss the king’s hand.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;“She deserves better than that,” said the king, and embraced her.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—George H. Allen, &lt;em&gt;The French Revolution&lt;/em&gt; (1923)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the evening, Louis signs the August Decrees and the &lt;em&gt;Declaration of the Rights of Man and of the Citizen&lt;/em&gt;. At midnight, La Fayette and his National Guard arrive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The forces of order, in the shape of Lafayette and 20,000 National Guardsmen, arrived in Versailles later that night after a forced march through an autumnal downpour. Lafayette had been reluctant to come at all, leaving Paris unpoliced and thereby risking accusations that he was in complicity with the demonstrators. But his men insisted, and crowds outside the Hôtel de Ville were muttering about stringing him and Bailly up if they continued to temporize. When he arrived all he could do was try to ensure that what the populace wanted was brought about without disorder, and he formally requested the king, in the name of Paris, to return to the capital with him and take up residence in the Tuileries palace. The king made no promises that night, but early the next morning a number of Parisians found their way into the palace precincts and were fired on by royal bodyguards. Thereupon an enraged mob poured into the palace, massacred two guardsmen, and almost broke into the queen’s apartments. Only prompt action by unco-ordinated units of the National Guard contained them, and Lafayette bundled the royal family onto the palace balcony to stand under his personal protection. The impact on the volatile crowd milling below was favourable, but constant shouts of ‘To Paris!’ made clear that only one thing would really satisfy them. Late in the morning of 6 October the king announced that he would go.   [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mob sneak through the Chapel Gate in the early morning, kill two guards—&lt;strong&gt;Miomandre de Sainte-Marie&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Tardivet du Repaire&lt;/strong&gt;—at the end of the Escalier de Marbre (Queen’s Marble Staircase), attempt to invade the Grand Appartement de la Reine but are stopped in the Queen’s Guard Room. Marie-Antoinette escapes from the Chambre de la Reine and takes refuge in the Grand Appartement du Roi, accompanied by princesse de Lamballe (in green, yet no historical record for her presence), and probably &lt;strong&gt;Adélaïde Genet, Madame Auguié&lt;/strong&gt; (in ivory, no credit found). In the Salon de l’Œil-de-Bœuf, they unite with Louis and the rest of the royal family—Madame Royale, Louis-Charles, and &lt;strong&gt;Élisabeth de France&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;Madame Élisabeth&lt;/strong&gt; (Anne Létourneau), Louis’s youngest sister (in white). The childern are attended by their governess &lt;strong&gt;Louise-Élisabeth de Croÿ, duchesse de Tourzel&lt;/strong&gt; (Louise Latraverse). Later, Madame Auguié told this waking nightmare to her sister Jeanne-Louise-Henriette Campan, Première femme de Chambre:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;About half-past four in the morning they heard horrible yells and discharges of firearms; one ran to the Queen to awaken her and get her out of bed; my sister flew to the place from which the tumult seemed to proceed; she opened the door of the antechamber which leads to the great guard-room, and beheld one of the Body Guard holding his musket across the door, and attacked by a mob, who were striking at him; his face was covered with blood; he turned round and exclaimed: “Save the Queen, madame; they are come to assassinate her!” She hastily shut the door upon the unfortunate victim of duty, fastened it with the great bolt, and took the same precaution on leaving the next room. On reaching the Queen’s chamber she cried out to her, “Get up, Madame! Don’t stay to dress yourself; fly to the King’s apartment!” The terrified Queen threw herself out of bed; they put a petticoat upon her without tying it, and the two ladies conducted her towards the oeil-de-boeuf. A door, which led from the Queen’s dressing-room to that apartment, had never before been fastened but on her side. What a dreadful moment! It was found to be secured on the other side. They knocked repeatedly with all their strength; a servant of one of the King’s valets de chambre came and opened it; the Queen entered the King’s chamber, but he was not there. Alarmed for the Queen’s life, he had gone down the staircases and through the corridors under the oeil-de-boeuf, by means of which he was accustomed to go to the Queen’s apartments without being under the necessity of crossing that room. He entered her Majesty’s room and found no one there but some Body Guards, who had taken refuge in it. The King, unwilling to expose their lives, told them to wait a few minutes, and afterwards sent to desire them to go to the oeil-de-boeuf. Madame de Tourzel, at that time governess of the children of France, had just taken Madame and the Dauphin to the King’s apartments. The Queen saw her children again. The reader must imagine this scene of tenderness and despair.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—&lt;em&gt;Memoirs of Madame Campan on Marie Antoninette and Her Court&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 2 (1909)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the request of La Fayette, the King and Queen confront the mob on the balcony facing the Cour de Marble:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;His Majesty himself has appeared with Lafayette on the balcony, and again appears: &lt;em&gt;Vive le Roi&lt;/em&gt; greets him from all throats; but also from some one throat is heard, ‘&lt;em&gt;Le Roi à Paris&lt;/em&gt;, The King to Paris!’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Her Majesty too, on demand, shows herself, though there is peril in it : she steps out on the balcony, with her little boy and girl. ‘ No children, &lt;em&gt;Point d’enfans&lt;/em&gt;! ‘ cry the voices. She gently pushes back her children; and stands alone, her hands serenely crossed on her breast: ‘Should I die,’ she had said, ‘I will do it.’ Such serenity of heroism has its eflPect. Lafayette, with ready wit, in his highflown chivalrous way, takes that fair queenly hand, and, reverently kneeling, kisses it: thereupon the people do shout &lt;em&gt;Vive la Reine&lt;/em&gt;. Nevertheless, poor Weber ‘saw’ (or even thought he saw; for hardly the third part of poor Weber’s experiences, in such hysterical days, will stand scrutiny) ‘one of these brigands level his musket at her Majesty,’—with or without intention to shoot; for another of the brigands ‘angrily struck it down.’&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Thomas Carlyle, &lt;em&gt;The French Revolution: A History&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 1 (1923)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Louis and the royal court moved to the Tuileries Palace in the afternoon of 6 October.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A procession 60,000 strong accompanied Louis XVI and his queen on their nine-hour journey back to his capital that afternoon. . . . Nevertheless in the history of the Revolution the ‘October Days’ were decisive. Louis XVI never returned to Versailles. Henceforth he and his family would be confined to Paris, as a British observer put it, ‘more like prisoners than Princes’.   [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;2-july-1790-mirabeaus-rendezvous-with-the-queen&quot;&gt;2 July 1790: Mirabeau’s rendezvous with the Queen&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The secret meeting of Mirabeau and Marie-Antoinette in the park of the Château de Saint-Cloud is substantiated:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On July 2d, he went to stay, as he often did, with his niece, Madame d’Aragon, at Passy. Very early in the morning of the following day, he took a cabriolet, and with his nephew, young du Saillant, disguised and acting as a postilion, drove through the quiet summer lanes which then led from Passy to Saint-Cloud. At an unfrequented entrance to the park he left the cabriolet and his nephew: a door was mysteriously opened to admit him and closed again.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;In a summer-house, in the highest part of the gardens of Saint-Cloud, Mirabeau met the Queen, alone.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . . One story has it (there are several differing versions) that when she first saw the man who she believed had “led a band of outlaws to assassinate” the royal family at Versailles, she drew back with “a movement of horror.” That passed. . . . But he won her, as he won everybody.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . . She spoke afterwards of the deep impression he made upon her. He himself alluded to the interview with a profound feeling, and often to her grace, her dignity, and her charm. Before they parted, it is said that he raised her hand to his lips: “Madame, the monarchy is saved!”&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;What is certain, is that the interview left him with a yet more resolute determination to serve her: that he imbued her with his master idea, of making the National party the King’s party, and that his influence upon her mind can be traced long after his death.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Stephen G. Tallentyre, &lt;em&gt;The Life of Mirabeau&lt;/em&gt;, (1912)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The confidential letters mentioned in the dialogue refer to Mirabeau’s &lt;em&gt;Notes to the Court&lt;/em&gt;, which were conveyed by Auguste d’Arenberg, comte de La Marck. From June 1790 to March 1791, Mirabeau averaged two notes a week to the Court. Fifty of them are preserved. Many were destroyed after Mirabeau’s death and the insurrection of 10 August 1792.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the afternoon M. Goguenot returned. He had 
still the seals of France about him, and he brought me a statement of all he had burnt. . . . The most voluminous was that from Mirabeau. It was tied up with a scheme for an escape, which he thought necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—&lt;em&gt;Memoirs of Madame Campan on Marie Antoninette and Her Court&lt;/em&gt;, Vol. 2 (1909)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifty of these notes still exist. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;14-july-1790-fête-de-la-fédération&quot;&gt;14 July 1790: &lt;em&gt;Fête de la Fédération&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The 14th of July approached: that day was regarded by the nation as the anniversary of its deliverance, and preparations were made to celebrate it with a solemnity calculated to elevate the souls of the citizens, and to strengthen the common bonds of union. A confederation of the whole kingdom was appointed to take place in the Champ de Mars; and there, in the open air, the deputies sent by the eighty-three departments, the national representatives, the Parisian guard, and the monarch, were to take the oath to the constitution. . . . The immense preparations were scarcely completed in time; all Paris had been engaged for several weeks in getting the arrangements ready by the 14th.   [FAM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the construction scene shown in the film involving Parisians from all occupations, during which time Camille and Lucile Desmoulins get engaged. This is however an anachronism: in reality, M. and M&lt;sup&gt;me&lt;/sup&gt; Duplessis did not sent their blessing until December 1790.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The vast space of the Champ de Mars was inclosed by raised seats of turf, occupied by four hundred thousand spectators. An antique altar was erected in the middle; and around it, on a vast amphitheatre, were the king, his family, the assembly, and the corporation. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A profound silence now reigned in the vast inclosure, and Lafayette, appointed that day to the command in chief of all the national guards of the kingdom, advanced first to take the civic oath. Borne on the arms of grenadiers to the altar of the country, amidst the acclamations of the people, he exclaimed with a loud voice, in his own name, and that of the federates and troops: “We swear eternal fidelity to the nation, the law, and the king; to maintain to the utmost of our power the constitution decreed by the national assembly, and accepted by the king; and to remain united with every Frenchman by the indissoluble ties of fraternity.” Forthwith the firing of cannon, prolonged cries of “Vive la nation!” “Vive le roi!” and sounds of music, mingled in the air. The president of the national assembly took the same oath, and all the deputies repeated it with one voice. Then Louis XVI. rose and said: “I, king of the French, swear to employ all the power delegated to me by the constitutional act of the state, in maintaining the constitution decreed by the national assembly and accepted by me.” The queen, carried away by the enthusiasm of the moment, rose, lifted up the dauphin in her arms, and showing him to the people, exclaimed: “Behold my son, he unites with me in the same sentiments.” At that moment the banners were lowered, the acclamations of the people were heard, and the subjects believed in the sincerity of the monarch, the monarch in the affection of the subjects, and this happy day closed with a hymn of thanksgiving.   [FAM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another anachronism: Danton was elected as a member of the Provisional Commune of Paris in January 1790, but the No. 46 of Camille Desmoulins’s &lt;em&gt;Révolutions de France et de Brabant&lt;/em&gt; was published on 5 October 1790—the first Anniversary of the October Days.
Desmoulins’s famous &lt;em&gt;Discours de la lanterne aux Parisiens&lt;/em&gt;—the defense of political violence earning him the title ““Procureur-général de la lanterne”—was nonetheless published in September 1789, before the founding of &lt;em&gt;Révolutions de France et de Brabant&lt;/em&gt;. All of them are asynchronized with the preparation of &lt;em&gt;Fête de la Fédération&lt;/em&gt; in June 1790.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concludes the narrative of the first year of the Revolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>In the Name of Liberté&amp;colon;&amp;nbsp; I. From Versailles to Bastille</title>
        <link>/2020/03/28/revolution-prelude.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/03/28/revolution-prelude.html</guid>
        <description>
&lt;p&gt;Introduction—Coronation of Louis XVI—Royal family in 1788—Summoning the Estates-General of 1789—Elections—Opening of the Estates-General—Tennis Court Oath—&lt;em&gt;Séance royale&lt;/em&gt; of 23 June—Riots of 12 July—Storming of the Bastille  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;introduction-a-companion-to-la-révolution-française-1989-film&quot;&gt;Introduction: A companion to &lt;em&gt;La Révolution française&lt;/em&gt; (1989 film)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is an event-by-event breakdown in the chronological order. &lt;strong&gt;Historical figures&lt;/strong&gt; are in bold text at their first appearances, with their corresponding (cast members) in parentheses. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General references&lt;/strong&gt; with [acronyms]:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[AP]  &lt;em&gt;Archives parlementaires de 1787 à 1860.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[FAM]  François-Auguste Mignet, &lt;em&gt;History of the French Revolution from 1789 to 1814&lt;/em&gt; (Bell &amp;amp; Daldy, London, 1868); translated from &lt;em&gt;Histoire de la Révolution française depuis 1789 jusqu’en 1814&lt;/em&gt; (Firmin Didot père &amp;amp; fils, Paris, 1824).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[WD]  William Doyle, &lt;em&gt;The Oxford History of the French Revolution&lt;/em&gt;, Second Edition (Oxford University Press, 2002).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[PM]  Peter McPhee, &lt;em&gt;The French Revolution 1789–1799&lt;/em&gt; (Oxford University Press, 2002).
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part One: &lt;em&gt;Les Années lumière&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first part of this six-hour historical film reenacts the last years of the Ancien Régime—from the convocation of the Estates-General of 1789 to the Insurrection of 10 August 1792.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;11-june-1775-coronation-of-louis-xvi&quot;&gt;11 June 1775: Coronation of Louis XVI&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prior to its grand opening sequence featuring the Grand Canal and the Bassin de Latone in the Gardens of Versailles, the films nonetheless begins with a pre-edit scene back to 1775, when the 17-year-old &lt;strong&gt;Maximilien de Robespierre&lt;/strong&gt; (Steve Carretero) delivers a Latin tribute to the newly crowned Louis XVI on behalf of his classmates at the Collège Louis-le-Grand, among whom stands the 15-year-old &lt;strong&gt;Camille Desmoulins&lt;/strong&gt; (Philip-James Valentini). This anecdote was noted down by abbé Liévin-Bonaventure Proyart, then Robespierre’s teacher at Louis-le-Grand and later his biographer:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;En 1775, Louis XVI, après la cérémonie de son sacre, fit son entrée solennelle dans Paris, accompagné de la reine et de la famille royale. Leurs majestés . . . s’arrêtèrent devant le collége de Louis-le-Grand, où elles furent complimentées par l’Université en corps. . . . et ce fut Robespierre que l’on chargea de le lui offrir au nom de ses condisciples, dans un discours en vers qu’avait composé son professeur. Le roi abaissa un regard de bonté sur ce jeune homme qui, élevé dans sa maison, devait un jour lui porter le premier coup de poignard. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Proyart, &lt;em&gt;La Vie de Maximilien de Robespierre&lt;/em&gt; (1850)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nevertheless, the record of this fateful encounter is generally considered unsubstantiated. Moreover, it could not happen in 1774 according to the caption, as Louis XVI was crowned in Reims Cathedral on 11 June 1775. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;royal-family-in-1788&quot;&gt;Royal family in 1788&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the opulent ball hosted in the Galerie des Glaces (Hall of Mirrors) of the Palace of Versailles, &lt;strong&gt;Louis XVI&lt;/strong&gt; (Jean-François Balmer) and &lt;strong&gt;Marie-Antoinette d’Autriche&lt;/strong&gt; (Jane Seymour, VF: Béatrice Delfe) make their first appearances. “Madame Déficit” is accompanied by her dancing partner &lt;strong&gt;Axel von Fersen&lt;/strong&gt; (Jean-Yves Berteloot), her superintendent &lt;strong&gt;Marie-Thérèse-Louise de Savoie-Carignan, princesse de Lamballe&lt;/strong&gt; (Gabrielle Lazure), and her favorite &lt;strong&gt;Gabrielle de Polastron, duchesse de Polignac&lt;/strong&gt; (Claudia Cardinale). Polignac sits closer to the Queen at the casino table, reflecting Lamballe’s gradual falling out of favor since 1785.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shortly afterwards, three royal childern appear at the Hameau de la Reine in the Petit Trianon of Versailles: Dauphin of France &lt;strong&gt;Louis-Joseph&lt;/strong&gt; (Benji Marcus) riding a pony, his elder sister &lt;strong&gt;Marie-Thérèse Charlotte&lt;/strong&gt;, or &lt;strong&gt;Madame Royale&lt;/strong&gt; (Katherine Flynn), and their younger brother &lt;strong&gt;Louis-Charles&lt;/strong&gt;, the future &lt;strong&gt;Louis XVII&lt;/strong&gt; (Sean Flynn). Katherine and Sean are Seymour’s daughter and son in real life. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;21-january-1789-summoning-the-estates-general&quot;&gt;21 January 1789: Summoning the Estates-General&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the film, &lt;strong&gt;Jacques Necker&lt;/strong&gt; (Raymond Gérôme), the esteemed Controller-General of Finances and Chief Minister of France, advices Louis XVI to summon the Estates-General in order to levy taxes to address the state deficit. This decision-making process is, however, much more tortuous in history, where the idea of restoring this legislative and consultative assembly after more than 170 years was first deliberated on the Assembly of Notables in 1787.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘It seems to me’, declared Lafayette in the bureau where he sat on 21 May, ‘that this is the moment for us to beseech His Majesty to fix, immediately, in order to render account to him of all measures and settle their happy outcome forever, the convocation of a truly national assembly.’ ‘What, Sir,’ burst out the Count d’Artois, the king’s brother, ‘are you calling for the Estates-General?’ ‘Yes, my lord,’ replied the young glory-hunter, ‘and even better than that.’  [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The date of the Estates-General was officially announced by the previous finance minister Étienne-Charles de Loménie de Brienne on 8 August 1788, before Necker’s return to office on 24 August. A royal edict—&lt;em&gt;Règlement des États généraux de 1789&lt;/em&gt;—was issued on 24 January, followed by the nationwide elections of the delegates from the three estates of realm. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;marchapril-1789-elections&quot;&gt;March–April 1789: Elections&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On 4 March 1789, inside a church in Guise, &lt;strong&gt;Camille Desmoulins&lt;/strong&gt; (François Cluzet) plans to run for Estates-General deputy, together with his father &lt;strong&gt;Jean-Benoist-Nicolas Desmoulins&lt;/strong&gt; (Jean-Marie Bernicat). Subsequently, Camille is compiling a Third-Estate &lt;em&gt;cahier de doléances&lt;/em&gt;—a list of grievances raised by commoners, mainly against the privileges of the First and Second Estates. Camille unfortunately fails the election. Omitted in the film, Jean-Benoist-Nicolas was nominated, but declined due to health reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disappointed Camille moves back to Paris. Walking down the Rue des Cordeliers (nowadays Rue de l’École-de-Médecine), meets &lt;strong&gt;Antoine Simon&lt;/strong&gt; (Alain Frérot) the shoemaker, and &lt;strong&gt;Louis Legendre&lt;/strong&gt; (Jean-François Stévenin) the butcher, both politicians-to-be. Seconds later, he greets his future wife &lt;strong&gt;Lucile Desmoulins&lt;/strong&gt; (Marie Bunel) and in-laws &lt;strong&gt;Claude-Étienne Laridon-Duplessis&lt;/strong&gt; (François Lalande) and &lt;strong&gt;Anne-Françoise-Marie Bois de Veix&lt;/strong&gt; (Geneviève Mnich). Apparently, M. Duplessis is not very fond of Camille at this moment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;. . . although Camille’s love for Lucile Duplessis grew with each meeting, his suit appeared too hopeless to be even hinted at to the girl’s parents. M. Duplessis would simply have laughed at him; Madame Duplessis might have been kinder, but she most certainly would not have consented to think of the young man as her daughter’s lover, desperately poor and desperately unsuccessful as he still was. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Violet Methley, &lt;em&gt;Camille Desmoulins: A Biography&lt;/em&gt; (1914)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few key figures during the coming Revolution are introduced next:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a Parisian bar, the wealth lawyer &lt;strong&gt;Georges Jacques Danton&lt;/strong&gt; (Klaus Maria Brandauer, VF: Bernard Murat), reluctant to enter politics, chats with the influential &lt;strong&gt;Honoré-Gabriel Riqueti, comte de Mirabeau&lt;/strong&gt; (Peter Ustinov, VF: Roger Carel), who, despite his noble status, is going to represent the Third Estate. &lt;strong&gt;Jean-Paul Marat&lt;/strong&gt; (Vittorio Mezzogiorno, VF: Michel Vigné), physician and scientist, has undertaken political writings, whose &lt;em&gt;Offrande à la Patrie&lt;/em&gt; was published earlier that year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not evident how the trajectories of Mirabeau, Danton, Desmoulins, Simon, Legendre, and Marat intersect in early 1789. Besides delineating the personal histories and dispositions of these characters, these scenes set up the community background of the future Club des Cordeliers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Mirabeau never conceals his passion for a colorful private life, Danton is known to be loyal to his wife &lt;strong&gt;Antoinette Gabrielle Danton&lt;/strong&gt; (Marianne Basler), who, in the film, is carrying their future son Antoine at this time. However, Gabrielle’s pregnancy as depicted seems not synchronized with Antoine’s birth in June 1790. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;5-may-1789-opening-of-the-estates-general&quot;&gt;5 May 1789: Opening of the Estates-General&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This historic convention opens in the magnificent Hôtel des Menus-Plaisirs in Versailles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The royal session took place the following day in the Salle des Menus Galleries, arranged in the form of an amphitheatre, were filled with spectators. The deputies were summoned and introduced according to the order established in 1614. The clergy were conducted to the right, the nobility to the left, and the commons in front of the throne at the end of the hall.  [FAM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the 1139 delegates are 291 clergmen, 270 nobles, and 578 commoners. As depicted in the film, Louis XVI delivers a short opening speech, whose text is modified from the documentation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sa Majesté&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Puisse, Messieurs, un heureux accord régner dans cette Assemblée, et cette époque devenir à jamais mémorable pour le bonheur et la prospérité du royaume ! c’est le souhait de mon cœur, c’est le plus ardent de mes vœux, c’est enfin le prix que j’attends de la droiture de mes intentions et de mon amour pour mes peuples. Puisse, Messieurs, un heureux accord régner dans cette Assemblée, et cette époque devenir à jamais mémorable pour le bonheur et la prospérité du royaume ! c’est le souhait de mon cœur, c’est le plus ardent de mes vœux, c’est enfin le prix que j’attends de la droiture de mes intentions et de mon amour pour mes peuples.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[AP, Tuesday 5 May 1789]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Charles-Louis-François de Paule de Barentin (Keeper of the Seals), Necker addresses to the assembly for three hours regarding the financial situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More notable figures show up in this reenactment:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sitting on the left-hand side of the Queen is &lt;strong&gt;Charles-Philippe, comte d’Artois&lt;/strong&gt;, the youngest brother of Louis XVI and the future &lt;strong&gt;Charles X&lt;/strong&gt; (André Penvern).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the front row of nobility, we see &lt;strong&gt;Gilbert du Motier, marquis de La Fayette&lt;/strong&gt; (Sam Neill, VF: Pierre Arditi). Even the 7-year-old Dauphin knows he is the hero of the American Independence War.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among the clergy is abbé &lt;strong&gt;Emmanuel-Joseph Sieyès&lt;/strong&gt; (Jean Bouchaud), political theorist and the author of &lt;em&gt;Qu’est-ce que le Tiers-État ?&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;em&gt;What Is the Third Estate?&lt;/em&gt;]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Camille Desmoulins, attending the convention as a spectator, greets his old classmate &lt;strong&gt;Maximilien de Robespierre&lt;/strong&gt; (Andrzej Seweryn), a Third-Estate deputy for Arras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the session, Desmoulins reunites with Robespierre at the latter’s place. On the table lays a copy of Jean-Jacques Rousseau, &lt;em&gt;Du contrat social; ou, Principes du droit politique&lt;/em&gt; (first edition printed in 1762). They recollect the words of an old lecturer at Louis-le-Grand, which are resonant with the core questions in abbé Sieyès’s &lt;em&gt;Qu’est-ce que le Tiers-État ?&lt;/em&gt; (1789):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;1º Qu’est-ce que le Tiers-État ? Tout. &lt;br /&gt;
2º Qu’a-t-il été jusqu’à présent dans l’ordre politique ? Rien. &lt;br /&gt;
3º Que demande-t-il ? À y devenir quelque chose.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[1. What is the Third Estate? Everything;  2. What has it been hitherto in the political order? Nothing;  3. What does it desire to be? To become something.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;20-june-1789-tennis-court-oath&quot;&gt;20 June 1789: Tennis Court Oath&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On June 4 1789, Louis-Joseph, Dauphin of France, dies at age seven of tuberculosis. Meanwhile, the tension between the estates in the convention ramps up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The immediate issue was that of voting procedures: while the Third Estate deputies refused to vote separately, the nobility was in favour (by 188 votes to 46) as, very narrowly, were the clergy (134 votes to 114). Ultimately, Louis’s acquiescence in the nobility’s demand for voting to be in three separate chambers galvanized the outrage of the bourgeois deputies.  [PM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A series of following events lead to the formation of the &lt;em&gt;Assemblée nationale&lt;/em&gt; on 17 June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By the second week of the month (June) third-estate patience was running out. Against their previous resolutions, they had already begun to organize themselves and establish procedures, and on 3 June they elected Bailly as their president. There was now constant talk of unilateral action, of declaring the ‘Commons’ to be the national assembly, and of proceeding to verification of powers on that basis without further reference to the other two orders. On 10 June this talk at last culminated in a formal motion, moved by Sieyès, that a final appeal should be sent to the other two orders to join at once in common verification. Failing that, the Commons would proceed anyway. . . . It all played into Sieyès’s hands, and by the seventeenth he felt able to propose the title he had always wanted. By then an overwhelming majority recognized that there was no sensible alternative, and the name National Assembly was adopted by 491 votes to 89.  [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its first president, &lt;strong&gt;Jean Sylvain Bailly&lt;/strong&gt; (Michel Duchaussoy), astronomer and member of the Académie des sciences and the Académie française, presides over the solemn &lt;em&gt;serment du Jeu de Paume&lt;/em&gt; on 20 June.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was feared that the majority of the clergy would recognise the assembly by uniting with it; and to prevent so decided a step, instead of hastening the royal sitting, they closed the Salle des Etats, in order to suspend the assembly till the day of the sitting. . . . At that time Bailly presided over the assembly. . . . At an appointed hour on the following day, he repaired to the Salle des Etats, and finding an armed force in possession, he protested against this act of despotism. In the meantime the deputies arrived, dissatisfaction increased, all seemed disposed to brave the perils of a sitting. . . . one named the Tennis-court; this proposition was well received, and the deputies repaired thither in procession. Bailly was at their head; the people followed them with enthusiasm; even soldiers volunteered to escort them, and there, in a bare hall, the deputies of the commons standing with upraised hands, and hearts full of their sacred mission, swore, with only one exception, not to separate till they had given France a constitution.  [FAM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Oath can be found in &lt;em&gt;Gazette nationale ou le Moniteur universel&lt;/em&gt;, the official newspaper during the Revolution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;« Nous jurons de ne jamais nous séparer de l’Assemblée nationale, et de nous réunir partout où les circonstances l’exigeraient, jusqu’à ce que la Constitution du royaume fût établie et affermie par des fondements solides. »&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[“We swear never to separate from the National Assembly and to meet wherever circumstances require until the kingdom’s Constitution is established and grounded on solid foundations.”]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;23-june-1789-séance-royale&quot;&gt;23 June 1789: &lt;em&gt;Séance royale&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This dramatic royal session is centered around the conflict between the privileged and the reformers, starting from the King’s declarations nullifying the decisions of the National Assembly:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sa Majesté&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . . Réfléchissez, Messieurs, qu’aucun de vos projets, aucune de vos dispositions ne peut avoir force de loi sans mon approbation spéciale. Ainsi, je suis le garant naturel de vos droits respectifs ; et tous les ordres de l’Etat peuvent se reposer sur mon équitable impartialité.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Toute défiance de votre part serait une grande injustice. C’est moi, jusqu’à présent, qui fais tout le bonheur de mes peuples ; et il est rare peut-être que l’unique ambition d’un souverain soit d’obtenir de ses sujets qu’ils s’entendent enfin pour accepter ses bienfaits.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Je vous ordonne, Messieurs, de vous séparer tout de suite, et de vous rendre demain matin chacun dans les Chambres affectées à votre ordre, pour y reprendre vos séances. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[AP, Tuesday 23 June 1789]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The subsequent confrontation is recorded by multiple sources. As recalled by its main participant,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Le grand-maître des cérémonies s’approcha de moi, et me dit : Monsieur, vous avez entendu l’ordre du roi ? Je lui répondit : . . . Je crois que la nation assemblée ne peut pas recevoir d’ordre. . . . À la vérité, Mirabeau prit la parole et, s’emportant contre le grand-maître des cérémonies, dit à-peu-près ce qu’on a répété depuis : « Allez dire à ceux qui vous envoient que la force desbaïonnettes ne peut rien contre la volonté de la nation : » on a beaucoup loué cette réponse, . . . &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Bailly, &lt;em&gt;Mémoires d'un témoin de la Révolution&lt;/em&gt;, Tome 1&lt;sup&gt;er&lt;/sup&gt; (1804)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A better-known version of Mirabeau’s defiance of the Grand Master of Ceremonies—&lt;strong&gt;Henri Evrard, marquis de Dreux-Brézé&lt;/strong&gt; (Sebastian Roché)—is found in Adolphe Thiers’s &lt;em&gt;Histoire de la Révolution française&lt;/em&gt;, Tome 1&lt;sup&gt;er&lt;/sup&gt; (1823):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;« Allez dire à votre maître que nous sommes ici par la puissance du peuple, et qu’on ne nous en arrachera que
par la puissance des baïonnettes. »&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[“Go and tell your master that we are here by the power of the people, and that nothing bu the power of bayonets shall drive us away.”]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A prominent figurant: Nicolas Sarkozy as the Third-Estate deputy second to the left of Mirabeau. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;1213-july-1789-riots-in-paris&quot;&gt;12–13 July 1789: Riots in Paris&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In these circumstances he (Louis XVI) made the final surrender. On 27 June he wrote to the presidents of the clerical and noble orders ordering them to join the National Assembly.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;. . . Responsible men now looked forward to a period of dignified calm, allowing a return to normality and social harmony. Yet as July began there was little sign of that. On 26 June four regiments were ordered from the frontiers to the Paris region, and around the same time the king asked the veteran Marshal de Broglie to assume supreme command. On 1 July more troops were ordered up, making a fivefold increase, to well over 20,000, in less than a week. Nobody could fail to notice the build-up, or the number of foreign regiments involved, presumed to be more reliable than French ones. . . . At Court, the queen and Artois remained determined to get rid of Necker. . . . By 11 July they thought they had found them. That afternoon, the minister was presented with a royal letter dismissing him and ordering him to leave the country immediately.   [WD]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Counteractions of the royal court include the dismissal of Necker and the military deterrent. Marching in the film are three infantry and one calvary troops. Judging by their uniforms, they are likely to be (in the order of appearance): the Swiss Régiment de Castellas, the French Régiment du Dauphin dragons, the French Régiment de Provence, and the Swiss Régiment de Salis-Samade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the following day, Sunday, the 12th of July, about four in the afternoon, Necker’s disgrace and departure became known at Paris. . . . In a short time the city was in the greatest confusion; crowds gathered together on every side; more than ten thousand persons flocked to the Palais Royal all affected by this news, ready for anything, but not knowing what measure to adopt. Camille Desmoulins, a young man, more daring than the rest, one of the usual orators of the crowd, mounted on a table, pistol in hand, exclaiming: “Citizens, there is no time to lose; the dismissal of Necker is the knell of a Saint Bartholomew for patriots! This very night all the Swiss and German battalions will leave the Champ de Mars to massacre us all; one resource is left; to take arms!” These words were received with violent acclamations. He proposed that cockades should be worn for mutual recognition and protection. “Shall they be green,” he cried, “the colour of hope; or red, the colour of the free order of Cincinnatus?” “Green! green!” shouted the multitude. The speaker descended from the table, and fastened the sprig of a tree in his hat. Every one imitated him. The chestnut-trees of the palace were almost stripped of their leaves . . .  [FAM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This inspiring speech at the Café de Foy near the Galerie de Montpensier in the Palais-Royal is vividly reenacted in the film. So is the attack on the multitude in the Tuileries Garden by the German Régiment Royal-Allemand cavalerie commanded by &lt;strong&gt;Charles Eugène de Lorraine, prince de Lambesc&lt;/strong&gt; (Mario Luraschi).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, Danton launches his political career by orating at the Club des Cordeliers, although its synchronization with the Parisian insurrections is probably fictional. Among the enthusiastic crowd are Marat, Legendre, Simon, and the Saint-Domingue distiller &lt;strong&gt;Claude Fournier l’Américain&lt;/strong&gt; (Georges Trillat). &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;14-july-1789-storming-of-the-bastille&quot;&gt;14 July 1789: Storming of the Bastille&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Bastille, demolished in late 1789, was “reconstructed” using the Château de Tarascon in Bouches-du-Rhône. Most narrative of this siege and sieze is historically accurate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The commanders of defense are &lt;strong&gt;Bernard René Jourdan, marquis de Launay&lt;/strong&gt; (Henri Serre), governor of the Bastille, and Lieutenant &lt;strong&gt;Ludwig von Flüe/Louis de Flue&lt;/strong&gt; (Philippe Chemin), commanding officer of the Swiss Guards from the Régiment de Salis-Samade. On the side of besiegers are &lt;strong&gt;Stanislas-Marie Maillard&lt;/strong&gt; (Patrick Tessari), the “capitaine des volontaires de la Bastille,” who stands on a plank over the moat to get the letter from de Launay, and &lt;strong&gt;Pierre-Augustin Hulin&lt;/strong&gt; (Bernard Lepinaux), who leads one of the two mutinous columns of Gardes Françaises. &lt;strong&gt;Jacques-Alexis Thuriot de la Rosière&lt;/strong&gt; (Michel Melki) serves as the negotiator between the two sides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;On the 13th the insurrection took at Paris a more regular character. . . .  A permanent committee was formed at the Hotel de Ville, to take measures for the general safety.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The next day . . . an alarm was given that the regiments stationed at Saint Denis were on the march, and that the cannon of the Bastille were pointed on the Rue Saint Antoine. The committee immediately sent to ascertain the truth; appointed bands of citizens to defend that side of the town, and sent a deputation to the governor of the Bastille, soliciting him to withdraw his cannon and engage in no act of hostility. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;A deputy of the district of Saint Louis de la Culture, named Thuriot de la Rosiere, then requested a parley with De Launay, the governor. When admitted to his presence he summoned him to change the direction of the cannon. The governor replied, that the cannon had always been placed on the towers, and it was not in his power to remove them; yet, at the same time, having heard of the alarm prevalent among the Parisians, he had had them withdrawn a few paces, and taken out of the port-holes. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;But the impatient crowd now clamoured for the surrender of the Bastille. From time to time the cry arose, “The Bastille! we will have the Bastille!” At length, two men, more determined than the rest, darting from the crowd, sprang on a guardhouse, and struck at the chains of the drawbridge with heavy hatchets. The soldiers shouted to them to retire, and threatened to  re; but they continued to strike, succeeded in breaking the chains and lowering the bridge, and then rushed over it, followed by the crowd. In this way they advanced to cut the chains of the second bridge. The garrison now dispersed them with a discharge of musketry. . . .&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The siege had lasted more than four hours when the French guards arrived with cannon. Their arrival changed the appearance of the combat. The garrison itself begged the governor to yield. The unfortunate De Launay, dreading the fate that awaited him, wished to blow up the fortress, and bury himself under its ruins and those of the faubourg. He went in despair towards the powder magazine, with a lighted match. The garrison stopped him, raised a white standard on the platform, and reversed the guns, in token of peace. . . . The governor, a few Swiss soldiers and Invalides were torn from the protection of those who sought to defend them, and put to death by the implacable crowd.  [FAM]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details can be found in Jacques Léon Godechot’s &lt;em&gt;La prise de la Bastille, 14 juillet 1789&lt;/em&gt; (1965). For instance,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The electors . . . decided to send a delegation to the Bastille. The delegates got there at about teno’clock. De launey received them in friendly fashion at his residence, the ‘Gouvernement’, and as it was lunch time he invited them to share his meal. . . . But the delegation did not go so far; it merely asked the governor to take such measures as might allay the people’s fears. De Launey assured the delegates that he would do no harm to the quartier Saint-Antoine, and gave orders for guns standing on the towers to be withdrawn and for the embrasures to be blocked with planks of wood.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;De Launay is lynched by the mob on the way to the Hôtel de Ville. Danton and Camille Desmoulins arrive at the Bastille after fortress has already fallen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the Palace of Versailles, served by his valet &lt;strong&gt;Jean-Baptiste Cléry&lt;/strong&gt; (Geoffrey Bateman), Louis XVI writes down the famous line in his diary:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Mardi . . . . 14  Rien. &lt;br /&gt;
[Tuesday . . . . 14  Nothing.]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At night, Louis is informed of the seriousness of the fall of the Bastille by &lt;strong&gt;François Alexandre Frédéric, duc de la Rochefoucauld-Liancourt&lt;/strong&gt; (Yves-Marie Maurin):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;— Mais c’est donc une révolte ? &lt;br /&gt;
— Non, sire, c’est une révolution !&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;[– Why, is this a revolt? — No, sire, it’s a Revolution!]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Reverberating the Artistry</title>
        <link>/2020/03/25/power-of-art.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2020/03/25/power-of-art.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the BERNINI and DAVID episodes of this figure-centered art history series, artworks, reenactments, and storytelling are painted with musical pieces from the Baroque and classical eras. This note is aimed at reviewing the pas de deux of art and music through these accessible examples.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following catalogue-ordered list is arranged in the format of&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Composer&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
        Musical piece (audio link) &lt;br /&gt;
        [&lt;strong&gt;Artist&lt;/strong&gt;, artwork]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;01  Claudio Monteverdi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mPhWDKT2gSk&quot;&gt;Madrigals, Book 8, “Hor che’l ciel e la terra e’l vento tace,” SV 147&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Gian Lorenzo Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ecstasy of Saint Teresa&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;02  Claudio Monteverdi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1Z1tpAsA2M8&quot;&gt;Madrigals, Book 8, “Altri canti di marte,” SV 155&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bust of Cardinal Scipione Borghese&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;03  Claudio Monteverdi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=N3XVvUxcIY0&quot;&gt;Madrigals, Book 8, “Lamento della ninfa,” SV 163: “Amor”&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;David&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;The Rape of Proserpina&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Apollo and Daphne&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;04  Claudio Monteverdi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=XIsliS7oz8s&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vespro della Beata Vergine&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Vespers for the Blessed Virgin&lt;/em&gt;), SV 206: Concerto, “Pulchra es”&lt;/a&gt; 
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bust of Costanza Bonarelli&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;05  Claudio Monteverdi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ODZ1laysiFI&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;L’incoronazione di Poppea&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Coronation of Poppaea&lt;/em&gt;), SV 308: Act III, “A Dio, Roma!”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ecstasy of Saint Teresa&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Bust of Costanza Bonarelli&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;06  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OJQ04_y6e6c&quot;&gt;Sonata in E-flat major “Al santo sepolcro,” RV 130: Largo molto&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ecstasy of Saint Teresa&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;07  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Bxp74hB-4Zw&quot;&gt;Nisi Dominus, RV 608: “Cum dederit” (Andante)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Jacques-Louis David&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Le Serment des Horaces&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Oath of the Horatii&lt;/em&gt;);
&lt;em&gt;Le Serment du Jeu de paume&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Tennis Court Oath&lt;/em&gt;); 
&lt;em&gt;Les licteurs rapportent à Brutus les corps de ses fils&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Lictors Bring to Brutus the Bodies of His Sons&lt;/em&gt;);
&lt;em&gt;La Mort de Marat&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Death of Marat&lt;/em&gt;)
]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;08  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=wqAx99Cigig&quot;&gt;Salve Regina, RV 616: “Et Jesum” (Andante molto)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;François Boucher&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Le Jugement de Pâris&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Judgment of Paris&lt;/em&gt;)]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;09  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Dzg91IyhIt8&quot;&gt;Stabat Mater, RV 621: “Cujus animam gementem”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[Bernini’s demolished bell towers for the St. Peter’s Basilica]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;10  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=j5lkTEKQiXM&quot;&gt;Stabat Mater, RV 621: “Eja mater, fons amoris”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Francesco Borromini&lt;/strong&gt;, San Carlo alle Quattro Fontane; &lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, Sant’Andrea al Quirinale]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;11  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zIxXMIie9XI&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Filiae Maestae Jerusalem&lt;/em&gt;, RV 638: “Sileant zephyri”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Blessed Ludovica Albertoni&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;12  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=zTXdQuWiWAw&quot;&gt;Cantata “Cessate, omai cessate,” RV 684: “A voi dunque ricorro”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Martyrdom of Saint Lawrence&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;13  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=66OJIcGSkKs&quot;&gt;Cantata “Cessate, omai cessate,” RV 684: “Nell’orrido albergo”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[End titles of BERNINI]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;14  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2QYuh9D1JEo&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;L’Olimpiade&lt;/em&gt;, RV 725: Sinfonia&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bust of Pope Gregory XV&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;Statue of Pope Urban VIII&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;15  Antonio Vivaldi&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VHUiG1TpBGU&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;L’Olimpiade&lt;/em&gt;, RV 725: Act II, “Gemo in un punto e fremo”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bacchanal: A Faun Teased by Children&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;em&gt;The Goat Amalthea with the Infant Jupiter and a Faun&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;16  George Frideric Handel&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=RmeFTM80NDk&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Rodelinda, regina de’ Longobardi&lt;/em&gt;, HWV 19: Act I, “Ombre, piante, urne funeste!”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[Château de Versailles; &lt;strong&gt;David&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Portrait d’Antoine-Laurent Lavoisier et de sa femme&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;17  George Frideric Handel&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=20Wy7kK_wGc&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Acis and Galatea&lt;/em&gt;, HWV 49: Act II, “I rage, I melt, I burn!”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Bernini&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Bust of Costanza Bonarelli&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;18  Michael Haydn&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=EUKFK2ezoCQ&amp;amp;t=21s&quot;&gt;Missa pro defuncto Archiepiscopo Sigismondo (Requiem in C minor), MH 155&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Élisabeth Vigée Le Brun&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Portrait de Marie-Antoinette à la rose&lt;/em&gt;; &lt;strong&gt;David&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Marie-Antoinette conduite à l’échafaud&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Marie Antoinette Led to Her Execution&lt;/em&gt;); &lt;em&gt;Autoportrait&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;19  Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=czpbVZI5-Pk&quot;&gt;Great Mass in C minor, K. 427/417a: Laudamus te (Allegro aperto)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Pierre Beaumarchais&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;La Folle Journée, ou le Mariage de Figaro&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Marriage of Figaro&lt;/em&gt;)]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;20  Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=eX9V768gCso&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maurerische Trauermusik&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Masonic Funeral Music&lt;/em&gt;) in C minor, K. 477/479a&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;David&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;La Mort de Marat&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;21  Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=nGTBCWnwzgI&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le nozze di Figaro&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Marriage of Figaro&lt;/em&gt;), K. 492: Act I, “Non so più cosa son, cos faccio”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Honoré Fragonard&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Les Hasards heureux de l’escarpolette&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Swing&lt;/em&gt;)]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;22  Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=BLtqZewjwgA&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Le nozze di Figaro&lt;/em&gt;, K. 492: Act III, “Sull’aria… che soave zeffiretto”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Jacques Hauer&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Portrait de Charlotte Corday&lt;/em&gt;]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;23  Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=FcA5_k2mq7c&quot;&gt;Aria for Soprano, “Alma grande e nobil core,” K. 578&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Jean-Baptiste Greuze&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Une fille avec un canari mort&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;A Girl with a Dead Canary&lt;/em&gt;)]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;24  Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fX5zsrC6hYk&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Die Zauberflöte&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;The Magic Flute&lt;/em&gt;), K. 620: Act I, “O zittre nicht, mein lieber Sohn”&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[&lt;strong&gt;Auguste Couder&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ouverture des États généraux à Versailles, 5 mai 1789&lt;/em&gt;; end titles of DAVID]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;25  &lt;strong&gt;Ludwig van Beethoven&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q3X5ZpLNILI&quot;&gt;Piano Sonata No. 14 in C♯ minor &lt;em&gt;“Quasi una fantasia”&lt;/em&gt;, Op. 27, No. 2 (&lt;em&gt;Moonlight&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
[Opening titles]
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The motif of &lt;strong&gt;Claude Joseph Rouget de Lisle&lt;/strong&gt;’s &lt;em&gt;La Marseillaise&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Chant de guerre pour l’armée du Rhin&lt;/em&gt; accompanies David’s Empire-style paintings during the Napoleonic era.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Music credits to the other six episodes: &lt;strong&gt;Peter Salem&lt;/strong&gt; (CARAVAGGIO), &lt;strong&gt;David Gale&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;Andy Bush&lt;/strong&gt; (REMBRANDT), &lt;strong&gt;Niraj Chag&lt;/strong&gt; (TURNER and PICASSO), &lt;strong&gt;David Julyan&lt;/strong&gt; (VAN GOGH), and &lt;strong&gt;Daniel Giorgetti&lt;/strong&gt; (ROTHKO)
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The World around the Knick&amp;colon; IA. The Playbill</title>
        <link>/2019/11/14/knick-summary-operations.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/11/14/knick-summary-operations.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Often as climaxes in the plot, dozens of surgical scenes are featured in the 20 episodes of &lt;em&gt;The Knick&lt;/em&gt;. Below is a list of the major operations with brief descriptions. Enclosed in the brackets are the participating surgeons, the first of whom leads the procedure. Chickering, by default, refers to Dr. Bertram “Bertie” Chickering, Jr. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;01  CESAREAN SECTION&lt;/strong&gt;  [Christiansen, Thackery, Gallinger, and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
In her third pregnacy, Mrs. Warren presents with a case of &lt;em&gt;placenta previa&lt;/em&gt;. A caesarean delivery is attempted, but saves neither Warren nor the fetus, which is the twelfth failure of the same procedure in succession. 
 (101) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;02  INTESTINE RESECTION&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Gallinger, Chickering, and Edwards] &lt;br /&gt;
After an abdominal surgery for his pelvis fracture, Mr. Gentile is infected with &lt;em&gt;septicemia&lt;/em&gt; from his lacerated bowel and develops a case of &lt;em&gt;bronchitis&lt;/em&gt;, which prohibits the usage of ether for general anesthesia. Thackery demonstrates &lt;em&gt;spinal anesthesia&lt;/em&gt; and removes the damaged section of the patient’s bowel with the help of an intestinal clamp he recently improved. 
 (101) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;03  UNKNOWN&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Gallinger, and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
An accident occurs during an operation when Chickering is testing the new electric cauterizer. The patient is set afire. Nurse Monk is electrocuted. 
 (102) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;04  AORTIC ANEURYSMORRHAPHY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Gallinger, and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
Mr. Olynyk is suffering from an &lt;em&gt;aortic aneurism&lt;/em&gt;. A resect-and-reconstruct procedure based on &lt;em&gt;Hunterian ligation&lt;/em&gt; is attempted, but fails. 
 (102) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;05  INGUINAL HERNIA REPAIR&lt;/strong&gt;  [Edwards] &lt;br /&gt;
In his underground operating room, Edwards invents a three-layer hernia procedure and performs it on Mr. Cockrell. The repair is successful, but the patient dies later as he ignores the postoperative instruction of refraining from strenuous activity. 
 (103) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;06  REATTACHMENT RHINOPLASTY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery] &lt;br /&gt;
Thackery performs the rhinoplasty procedure for Mrs. Alford (Abigail Healey), infected with &lt;em&gt;syphilis&lt;/em&gt;, using her biceps muscle pedicle flap. 
 (103) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;07  INTESTINAL PERFORATION CLOSURE&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
Cora Hemming develops a case of intestine perforation as a complication of her &lt;em&gt;typhoid fever&lt;/em&gt;. During the operation, two sections of her bowel are successfully stitched together to a fold in her peritoneum. 
 (103) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;08  FILI-GALVANOPUNCTURE OF ANEURYSMS&lt;/strong&gt;  [Edwards, Gallinger, Thackery, and Chickering]&lt;br /&gt;
The doctors save Mr. Gatchell from his aortic aneurysm following a gavanic procedure that combines wire insertion and electrothrombosis. Edwards coauthors the original paper. 
 (104) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;09  UTERINE PERFORATION CLOSURE&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Harriet, and Chickering]&lt;br /&gt;
A Slovakian woman performs a surgical abortion on herself. The bleeding on her left uterine wall evetually leads to her death. 
 (104) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;10  TRAUMA SURGERY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery and Edwards] &lt;br /&gt;
Thackery saves a leg of Bunky Collier’s brother-in-law from being amputated by removing a bullet lodged in the tunica. 
 (105) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;11  INGUINAL HERNIA REPAIR&lt;/strong&gt;  [Edwards] &lt;br /&gt;
Edwards improves his inguinal hernia procedure by using silver wires as the medical suture for Mr. Mendieta. 
 (105) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;12  CESAREAN SECTION&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
During her labor, Mrs. Lefkowitz is diagnosed with an extreme case of &lt;em&gt;placenta previa&lt;/em&gt;. A C-section is performed in 72 seconds, but fails again. 
 (105) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;13  BLOODLETTING&lt;/strong&gt;   [Gallinger and Harriet] &lt;br /&gt;
Almost in a state of desperation, Gallinger performs &lt;em&gt;venesection&lt;/em&gt; (or &lt;em&gt;phlebotomy&lt;/em&gt;) on his own daughter Lillian to save her from &lt;em&gt;meningitis&lt;/em&gt;. This despairing effort results in failure.
 (106) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;14  CESAREAN SECTION&lt;/strong&gt;   [Thackery and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
By inventing the method of &lt;em&gt;intrauterine balloon tamponade&lt;/em&gt;, which significantly reduces the danger of &lt;em&gt;postpartum hemorrhage&lt;/em&gt;, Thackery and Chickering safely deliver the baby of a six-time multigravida. 
 (106) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;15  APPENDECTOMY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Christiansen and Thackery] &lt;br /&gt;
Thackery demonstrates the method of finding the appendix of an &lt;em&gt;appendicitis&lt;/em&gt; patient, and Christiansen proves its surgical removal. Dr. William Halsted attends the operation. 
 (107) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;16  TRACHEOTOMY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery] &lt;br /&gt;
Thackery saves Ping Wu from choking by performing an emergency &lt;em&gt;tracheotomy&lt;/em&gt;. 
 (107) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;17  TRAUMA SURGERY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Edwards, Chickering, and Gallinger]  &lt;br /&gt;
The doctors attempt to save Officer Phineas Sears, who gets multiple stab wounds at his lung, liver, and kidney. Sears dies after the first operation due to &lt;em&gt;internal hemorrhage&lt;/em&gt;. 
 (107) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;18  TRAUMA SURGERIES&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Edwards, Gallinger, Chickering, Harriet, and Williams]  &lt;br /&gt;
The staffs of the Knickerborker Hospital and the Minetta Negro Infirmary treat a large number of injurers from the street riot.
 (107) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;19  CERVICOFACIAL ACTINOMYCOSIS SURGERY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Edwards, and Gallinger]  &lt;br /&gt;
While removing the abscess from the patient’s mental foramen, Thackery cannot finish the procedure due to his cocaine withdrawl. Edwards takes over the scalpel. 
 (108) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;20  BRAIN TUMOR SURGERY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Edwards, and Chickering]  &lt;br /&gt;
Before dealing with the tumor, Thackery relieves the patient’s intracranial pressure through &lt;em&gt;cranial trephination&lt;/em&gt;. The hole is left open after the operation. 
 (110) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;21  SPLENECTOMY&lt;/strong&gt; [Zinberg] &lt;br /&gt;
Zinberg operates on a &lt;em&gt;splenic anemia&lt;/em&gt; patient by surgically removing his spleen.  (110) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;22  BLOOD TRANSFUSION&lt;/strong&gt; [Thackery] &lt;br /&gt;
Thackery transfuses his own blood to a young patient suffering from &lt;em&gt;anemia&lt;/em&gt; caused by &lt;em&gt;chlorosis&lt;/em&gt;. The girl is killed as a result of Thackery’s erroneous understanding of human blood types.  (110) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;23  RHINOPLASTY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery] &lt;br /&gt;
Thackery performs a cosmetic surgery on a female Cromartie patient using her “golden” earring as an insert. 
 (201) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;24  CHOLECYSTECTOMY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Chickering and Edwards] &lt;br /&gt;
During the operation, Edwards supervises Chickering to separate and ligate the two &lt;em&gt;cystic arteries&lt;/em&gt; within the patient’s &lt;em&gt;cystohepatic triangle&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;Calot’s triangle&lt;/em&gt;.
 (201) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;25  TUBERCULAR OSTEOMYELITIS SURGERY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Chickering and Mays] &lt;br /&gt;
Chickering leads the procedure and dissects the abscess down to the bone to release the pus. Meanwhile, Mays shows incompetence of the surgical techique.
 (201) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;26  RETINAL DETACHMENT REPAIR&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery] &lt;br /&gt;
The previous fight left Edwards’ retina almost separated from the rear wall of his left eye. An incision on the sclera is intended to release the subretinal fluid and thus have the retina in contact with the &lt;em&gt;choroid&lt;/em&gt;. The operation, however, is terminated at its beginning due to Thackery’s drug withdral and hallucinations.
 (202) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;27  HEPATIC CANCER SURGERY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Gallinger and Edwards]  &lt;br /&gt;
The doctors attempt to remove a tumor on the inferior surface of the patient’s liver. Edwards instructs Gallinger to bisect the healthy liver tissue leading to the tumor and tie off all blood vessles contained within.
 (203) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;28  TRACHEOTOMY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Mays] &lt;br /&gt;
While cauterizing the incision, Mays ignites the flammable ether and is killed by the fire. 
 (204) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;29  PYROTHERAPY OF NEUROSYPHILIS&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery and Edwards] &lt;br /&gt;
(Not a surgery)  Thackery elevates Abigail’s body temperature to 106 degrees Fahrenheit through the injection of malaria parasites. A higher therapeutic fever induced in a hypertherm cabinet effectively kills the &lt;em&gt;syphilis spirochetes&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;Treponema pallidum&lt;/em&gt;). Her malaria is subsequently cured by &lt;em&gt;quinine&lt;/em&gt;.
 (204) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;30  TOPECTOMY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery] &lt;br /&gt;
Experimenting on Mr. Sidney Carton, who loses the top of his cranium but retains an intact brain, Thackery elicits the motional and emotional responses of the patient by stimulating selected points of his brain with electric currents. Furthermore, using a rheoscope, Thackery identifies a brain spot excited after injecting the patient with a dose of morphine. In a subsequent operation, Thackery surgically removes the “morphine region,” but leaves Carton in a vegetative state.
 (205) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;31  TRAUMA SURGERIES&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Edwards, Gallinger, and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
The staff of the Knick treat 124 injurers from the construction accident of the New York City subway system, in which six people die and 150 wounded.
 (205) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;32  ESOPHAGEAL CANCER SURGERY&lt;/strong&gt;  [Chickering, Edwards, and Zinberg] &lt;br /&gt;
Several experimental methods are employed to treat the esophageal tumor of Anne Chickering, Bertie’s mother. After trying &lt;em&gt;Röntgenotherapy&lt;/em&gt;, Bertie and Edwards attempt an ionic surgery by passing electric currents through mercury-coated zinc needles inserted into the tumor. After confirming its inefficacy, Bertie decides on the highly risky &lt;em&gt;laryngectomy&lt;/em&gt;, which fails not unexpectedly due to the complex attachment of the tumor with the laryngeal, tracheal, and esophageal tissues.
 (206) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;33  SEPARATION OF OMPHALOPAGUS TWINS&lt;/strong&gt;  [Thackery, Edwards, Gallinger, and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
Through X-ray examination, Thackery concludes that the only vital organ that Zoya and Nika—a pair of Minsk-borned twins conjoined by a band of cartilage and soft tissue in their midsection—share is their liver. After devising a procedure to bisect the liver with little hemorrhaging, the surgical team, including four doctors and six nurses, separate the twins after a three-and-a-half-hour battle. The entire operation is filmed by a motion picture camera.
 (207) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;34  UMBILICAL HERNIA REPAIR&lt;/strong&gt;  [Edwards and Gallinger] &lt;br /&gt;
Mr. Garrison Carr is paralyzed on the operating table after Edwards injects his muscles attached to the aponeurotic membrane with a &lt;em&gt;curare&lt;/em&gt; solution secretly distilled by Gallinger, who then saves Carr in the emergency by a tracheotomy. 
 (207) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;35  SEPTOPLASTY&lt;/strong&gt; [Thackery and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
Thackery plans to place a celluloid insert into Abigail’s nasal cavities to support her reconstructed nose. Abruptly, Abigail dies of an anesthetic reaction before the operation starts. 
 (208) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;36  INTESTINE RESECTION&lt;/strong&gt; [Thackery, Gallinger, and Chickering] &lt;br /&gt;
Traumatized by Abigail’s sudden death of general anesthesia, Thackery insists on demonstrating a self-surgery and resecting his own necrotic intestine sections to promote spinal anesthesia. While continuing the procedure despite the unancipatedly complicated necrosis, Thackery accidentally cuts his abdominal aorta and loses his life in his own operating room.
 (210) &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rethink the Programmed Life</title>
        <link>/2019/01/06/programmed-life.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2019/01/06/programmed-life.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It’s the first week of a new year. Looking back, historians have attached tags to the distinct epochs of modern history: the Renaissance, the Enlightenment, the Industrial Age, the Information Age, etc. While it’s premature to anticipate what’s coming next, the new millennium does reveal a few signatures, among which is the near-frictionless flow of common knowledge. “Journal” and “encyclopedia” are now more frequently denoting websites than giant volumes in libraries. Tens of languages are being taught online for free. Advanced learning is no longer confined within classrooms. Even elite universities are opening their doors to the middle class and underrepresented groups. The general public have never been so close to understanding and contributing to the frontiers of human civilization. The creativities of our species are being unleashed to an unprecedented extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The accessibility of knowledge, together with the improvement in life quality and social equality, should, in principle, prompt a generation-wide desire for independent thinking and pioneering ventures. Yet it’s hardly being epitomized by the graduates of higher education institutions in general, including those from the most prestigious universities. Another trend is nevertheless pronounced—standardization: Among my friends pursing non-academic careers, around nine out of ten choose finance, consulting, or information technology, regardless of their backgrounds in college or graduate school. A fraction of those staying in academia—fortunately, not all of them—instead of enjoying the privileges of free inquiry and organized skepticism, seem to be more devoted to the cyclic game of grant-applying, result-producing, publishing, and advertising, to whom solid knowledge is merely a byproduct of their arduous work. Alternative options are occasionally considered as “unconventional” career paths, which may arouse curiosity, if not sympathy, among the ones in “mainstream” industries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One has no reason to be disturbed if all these choices are based on clear self-awareness. In fact, a large fraction of them are not. In 1883, when addressing at the American Association for the Advancement of Science, physicist Henry A. Rowland pondered the fate of human creativity in the midst of the Second Industrial Revolution:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Man is a gregarious animal, and depends very much, for his happiness, on the sympathy of those around him; and it is rare to find one with the courage to pursue his own ideals in spite of his surroundings. … To-day the railroad and the telegraph, the books and the newspapers, have united each individual man with the rest of the world: instead of his mind being an individual, a thing apart by itself, and unique, it has become so influenced by the outer world, and so dependent upon it, that it has lost its originality to a great extent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rowland mourned the past ages of masters, and yet failed to foresee more great minds would emerge in the following century. However, what he pointed out as the suppression of individuality due to ubiquitous connections isn’t far from the truth. But it shouldn’t be simply attributed to the indecisive nature of human minds—through industrialization, a new “cult of progress” was formed, worshiping productivity, fortune, and competition. Followers are supposed to play according to the rules, contributing one’s time and intelligence in exchange for payment and recognition. A reward system was set up, acclaiming whoever outperforming their peers and elevated along the pyramid. Those reluctant to join are marginalized economically and socially. Nowadays, such systems are reigning over every sophisticated profession—business, technology, politics, law, as well as a substantial portion of academic research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One has to acknowledge that, in almost every aspect, the development of modern society has been greatly accelerated by the cult of progress. But I feel a bit uneasy to see it becoming autocratic—while stimulating the most vigorous minds, it imposes the pressure of abandoning originality and long-term goals for instant success, and evokes a sense of failure to those hesitating to participate. Across the intellectual spectrum, pioneering accomplishments are rarely fruits of hypercompetition, opportunism, or populism. Instead, they are more likely to be crafted by genuine passion, determination, and the ability to pinpoint truly significant problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Decisions are left for us to make. As far as I’m concerned, the foundation of education shouldn’t be the acquisition of professional skills, nor the so-called critical thinking and problem-solving, even if they can be well defined. It is the formation of values—a set of underivable yet influenceable guidelines on what we appreciate and distain, and what motivates us, in the first place, to think and act. If there happens to be a voice inside us yearning for more than a programmed life, why not listen to it and see what it leads to. After all, its chance to survive, given the overall prosperity and openness of the new millennium, should exceed that at any time in the past. And we might be able to taste a pleasure not accessed by many—unlike winning or profiting, being how we boastfully call ourselves: &lt;em&gt;sapiens&lt;/em&gt;. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 06 Jan 2019 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Turbulence of Metamorphosis</title>
        <link>/2018/12/09/my-fair-lady.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2018/12/09/my-fair-lady.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/em&gt; isn’t a love story or a princess myth. It is a story of transformation, though perhaps not the one we expect.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;p align=&quot;right&quot;&gt;—Alexis Gargagliano, in &lt;em&gt;Lincoln Center Theater Review&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Indeed. For years, I’d been left the impression of &lt;em&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/em&gt; being a fairy tale—charming, vibrant, witty, yet too miraculous to be real, too elegant to be affecting—until I walked into the Vivian Beaumont Theater, where I was showered with immense joy and pain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lerner &amp;amp; Loewe’s comedy isn’t merely about how individual lives could be reshaped by phonetics in unexpected ways, and it extends beyond a reflection on gender roles and social classes in Edwardian England. At the heart of &lt;em&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/em&gt; are the elations and tears of the ones wishing to rewrite their fates, and the inherent intellectual strength and emotional weakness of human beings. While laughing and clapping, we might suddenly discover the bittersweet lesson behind the amusing story, the moment we start suspecting if the front curtain is just a mirror.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A considerable fraction of the fascination of &lt;em&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/em&gt; originates from the straight play it is based on—George Bernard Shaw’s &lt;em&gt;Pygmalion&lt;/em&gt;. But the creativities of Alan Jay Lerner and Frederick Loewe aren’t secondary—musicalizing &lt;em&gt;Pygmalion&lt;/em&gt; without diluting its linguistic charm and dramatic tension would be a delicate task. Lerner and Loewe did it respectfully—the storyline, characters, and spoken dialogue of their musical are mostly inherited from the play. Consequently, the depth and sharpness of the Shavian classic are very well preserved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However great the book is, any musical would pale without its score. “‘What is too silly to be said may be sung’—well, yes; but what is too subtle to be said, or too deeply felt, or too revealing or too mysterious—these things can also be sung and only be sung.” The remark by Kenneth Clark in his &lt;em&gt;Civilisation&lt;/em&gt; can’t be better illustrated by &lt;em&gt;My Fair Lady&lt;/em&gt;—when the dialogue takes a breath, music cuts in, amplifying the exhilaration, believes, wishes, prejudice, disdain, or confusion of the roles, then gives the floor back to words. Verbal wits and sensual pleasures constructively interfere, performing a duet that is delightfully serious and seriously delightful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, music possesses a unique descriptive power. Songs form characters, often nearly define them—the whistling cockneys at Covent Garden, the grumbling servants at 27A Wimpole Street, the aristocratic gathering at Ascot, the mindlessly-in-love Freddy, and—the most vivid of all—Alfred P. Doolittle, the dancing and orating epicurean who can barely afford liquors but not morals. The hero and heroine, however, can’t be delineated even by five songs each. One has to go through every single line to decode the impetus of their fates.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-invincible-galatea&quot;&gt;The invincible Galatea&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She wasn’t noble, but had no fear. She sought from the crowd for witness to protect herself against the mistaken charge. She insisted on checking the “detective’s” notebook to ensure she’s free of accusation. She promised to call the police if being mistreated in the “boarding school.” She greeted a scorning gentleman with the spirit of a true citizen: “I’ve a right to be here if I like, same as you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was poor, but never fell. She never drinks despite her bibulous family. She won’t be tempted by gold and diamonds. She struggled for her lodging, whereas still dreamed of warmth and love. As she constantly reminds herself and the world: “I’m a good girl, I am!”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would be a huge mistake to think the pre-metamorphosis Eliza merely as a boisterous flowergirl desperate for every tuppence. Although in a less graceful condition, she lived with dignity, discipline, and hope. But nothing could match her knocking on the door of 27A Wimpole Street to negotiate the details of that mocking offer of speech training—she managed to filter out the condescendence, and seize the opportunity to learn and reform. She wouldn’t be easily hurt, but never supplicated. She reasoned that English lessons shouldn’t cost more than French lessons, and yet proposed a tuition that surprised the celebrated phoneticist, considering her limited income.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An experiment was launched, but yields unanticipated results: After four months, at the Ascot races, she already acquired a glorious pronunciation, yet didn’t know what to talk. Six weeks later, at the Embassy Ball, she could speak and behave like the most charming princess. The linguistic experiment per se should be called a success. Nevertheless, Eliza is transformed into not a lady but a perfect doll, who can only be manipulated and rely on the kindness of others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Earlier on that cold spring night, she sat on a dustcart, picked up cabbage leaves as fans, and sang the sweetest melody in London:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All I want is a room somewhere; &lt;br /&gt;
Far away from the cold night air. &lt;br /&gt;
With one enormous chair; &lt;br /&gt;
Oh, wouldn’t be loverly? &lt;br /&gt;
. . . &lt;br /&gt;
Someone’s head restin’ on my knee; &lt;br /&gt;
Warm and tender as he can be, &lt;br /&gt;
Who takes good care of me; &lt;br /&gt;
Oh, wouldn’t it be loverly?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Six months later, she sits in a luxurious armchair next to a fireplace, without feeling a bit of warmth. She converses with duchesses, dances with princes, yet not receiving any care. She hurls the slippers at her Professor and escapes from her private school. At Covent Garden, besides the old columns and folks, she hums her &lt;em&gt;Loverly&lt;/em&gt; tune, weeping. She now belongs to nowhere—too genteel to be a flowergirl, yet too weak to be a lady. She gets everything in her dream, but nothing is lovely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not the end of the transformation. It’s only the beginning, the first step in a new world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She leaves her egocentric and manipulative tutor. She dries her tears and moves on—this time, with an elegant speech and an indomitable heart, which has endured the pains as she learns to tell “Spain” from “Spine,” domination from care, limerence from love, and etiquette from respect. She doesn’t mind evolving into a more cultured Ms. Doolittle, and meanwhile will remain that &lt;em&gt;loverly&lt;/em&gt; Eliza.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the making of the fairest lady.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-vulnerable-pygmalion&quot;&gt;The vulnerable Pygmalion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He lives in his profession. He invents his own universal alphabets and arranges his home like a phonetic laboratory. He can pronounce 130 different vowels and place a person by their accent within six miles in England or two miles in London. To him, an articulate speech is a divine gift from the God:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Think what you’re dealing with. The majesty and grandeur of the English language. It’s the greatest possession we have. The noblest sentiments that ever flowed in the hearts of men are contained in its extraordinary, imaginative and musical mixtures of sounds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He sincerely believes so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world of Henry Higgins is simple and orderly—he uses the laws of linguistics or science in general as the measure of everything. In his mind, humans are classified according to their speeches, and the attractiveness of a person is determined by either their intellectual capacity or the uniqueness of their dialect. He despises anyone who “incarnates insult to English language” regardless of their gender, look, status, or occupation. He has equally low esteem for the uneducated populace and the pretentious, empty-headed nobles. He detests all characters against rationality, independence, and serenity. He is extremely principled, and assumes his principles ought to be obeyed by the whole civilized world. Of course, they aren’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His contentious beliefs are challenged by Eliza. He can’t understand why the grand success of his experiment leads to her emotional breakdown. Moreover, he observes a strange feeling that has never existed before:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I was serenely independent and content before we met; &lt;br /&gt;
Surely I could always be that way again—and yet &lt;br /&gt;
I’ve grown accustomed to her looks; &lt;br /&gt;
Accustomed to her voice; &lt;br /&gt;
Accustomed to her face. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At Mrs. Higgins’ place, he is defeated by the new Lady Eliza. He encounters his own coldness and arrogance. He is told how hurtful his words and deeds can be, and that he plays nothing but a replaceable role to any living creature. Yet he has no choice but to confess—acknowledging the truth complies with his values more than pretending to be deaf.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 2018 Lincoln Center Theater production ends in an air of melancholy—Eliza enters with her voice played on a gramophone, delivers her famous last line, and exits downstage, slowly disappearing from Higgins’ sight. Note that aisles haven’t been used as exits in interior scenes throughout the show, which, in my opinion, implies Eliza’s last presence is imaginary. In reality, as she promised, she never sees him again. He bids farewell to her—a rare counterpart of him, who truly appreciates his enthusiasm, shares his perseverance, and perceives his frailty. He will start a new chapter of his life, this time, learning to be a human.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;being-transformed-who-are-we&quot;&gt;Being transformed, who are we?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Higgins’ lady training program isn’t purely fictitious—in reality, we call it education, the systematic procedure through which young people may change their fates. Many are undergoing a metamorphosis no easier than that of Eliza, especially those pursuing higher education at a prestigious university in a foreign country.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m now a few years older than Eliza, yet still struggling to accurately pronounce the fifteen distinct vowels in American English: the near-close near-front unrounded /ɪ/, the near-close near-back rounded /ʊ/, etc. I’m rebuilding my vocabulary, using the handbooks intended for teenagers or those without a decent education. I’m assimilating a different set of attitudes and methods in scientific research. I’m resetting my knowledge, especially that on social sciences and humanities. I’m acquiring the basic skills of writing and communication. I’m overhauling my manners and values. There are nights I couldn’t put my books down, either too concentrated or too occupied. There are also “The Rain in Spain” moments, when “at once my heart took flight.” I’m surrounded by enlightening mentorships, as well as aimless zeal. I’ve be constantly encouraged, yet occasionally mocked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re exploring a world we’ve never been to. We’re being transformed into someone we aren’t familiar with. We’re approaching thousands of new excitements, yet distanced from many simple joys. We’re gaining knowledge and achievements, but they don’t naturally bring care or love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We can spend a night dancing or weeping. But when the morning is smearing up the sky, we’d go back to our phonetic charts, or any endeavor we choose to undertake.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most importantly, however “ladylike” we’ll become in the coming years, never let the spirit of that vigorous, fearless flowergirl be taken away from us—that’s what launched the transformation, and what essentially powers it. Some day in the future, when hesitating or lost, we shall recall the courage inside us the moment we knocked on the door of our 27A Wimpole Street and said:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I washed my face and hands before I come. If you were a gentleman, you would ask me to sit down.”&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 09 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Duties of Scientists</title>
        <link>/2018/12/01/the-duties-of-scientists.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2018/12/01/the-duties-of-scientists.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We are living in an era when scientific research, like trade and manufacture, has grown into a sophisticated social activity—flourishing, dynamic, and highly organized. The thrill of glancing through publications on high-profile academic journals can only be matched by that of watching fluyts sailing into and out of the 17th-century Amsterdam or Model Ts coming off the 1920s Ford assembly line. But the prosperity of science doesn’t provide straightforward answers to two classes of questions: those on the origin of science and those on its destination—namely, &lt;em&gt;why we do science&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;what science is used for&lt;/em&gt;. We’ve been forced to reconsider the relation between science and human society by a series of disconcerting events, which are, in recent years, becoming more perplexing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A few days ago, it was announced that two gene-edited babies have been born in China. Interestingly, the academia and the market reacted oppositely to this controversial leap: Scientists around the world are overwhelmingly denouncing this clinical application as irresponsible, unethical, and medically unnecessary. But investors seemed to find the smell of success—top stocks on gene-editing technology unanimously traded higher. Accessible information indicates this in-human trial is most likely to be funded by private capital and aimed at commercial interests. And the so-called “unexpected leakage” of results is in fact carefully orchestrated. Notably, this one-year-and-nine-month experiment would be impossible without an interdisciplinary team including experts in gene editing, sequencing, in vitro fertilization, animal testing, financing, and publicity, as well as the participation of an HIV care organization and the permission from medical regulation agencies. All these professionals collaborated quietly and introduced the twins to our world, without realizing the mark they would add to the timeline of human evolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But to me, the Theranos case—first revealed in 2015 and still under investigation—is even more terrifying: a nine-billion-dollar biotech unicorn could be built entirely on deception, and yet had won enormous acclaims—a charismatic young founder, a “revolutionary” blood-testing technology, over 700-million-dollar investment, a board of directors including seven eminent statesmen, and in every aspect, a new Silicon Valley miracle. Science, medicine, business, law, and media—most brilliant inventions of human beings—were maneuvered by their best practitioners to mislead doctors, endanger patients, and defraud investors in the name of ideas, innovations, and “changing the world.” The meticulously designed fraud could be continuing had it not been for an investigative reporter with &lt;em&gt;The Wall Street Journal&lt;/em&gt; and a brave young man—the grandson of a Theranos trustee and former US Secretary of State.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technological hypes have never appeared so frequently while being keenly applauded. What should be condemned aren’t the moral wrongs of a few individuals. It’s a culture, which most STEM students are currently immersed in, that needs to be reexamined—the one that prioritizes &lt;em&gt;what sounds cool&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;what pays more&lt;/em&gt;, instead of finding out &lt;em&gt;what benefits the society in the long term&lt;/em&gt;. We are surrounded by the view that the ultimate goal of scientific research is commercialization. We are being indoctrinated in a narrow definition of success that puts impact, fame, and reward ahead of anything else. We might occasionally find our education distanced from the basic mission of science—to answer, to our best knowledge, &lt;em&gt;what is true&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;what is not true&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;what we don’t know&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I can foresee a tragedy if science is one day dominated by the rules of the business world and loses the values of its own. An often overlooked point is: at the most fundamental level, science reshapes the world not because it makes people more productive, creative, or competitive—though it does—but because while establishing it people learn to be respectful to truths. Outside their laboratories, scientists have to watch closely how the knowledge they created is applied to the real world. They shoulder the obligations to prevent science from being misinterpreted or misused, and to ensure that our greatest intellectual endeavor is serving the common good, or—as a tribute to an old address—of, by, and for the humanity. I say the most irreplaceable role of scientists in the modern society is that of a navigator—leading the crew to catch the ocean currents and avoid the icebergs, and sharing their unbiased information on the best routes for the ship to move on.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Second Childhood</title>
        <link>/2018/11/18/a-second-childhood.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">/2018/11/18/a-second-childhood.html</guid>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For a while I’ve been finding myself younger than I look, sometimes almost a schoolboy:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m curious about how a sewing machine stitches, how a horn pitches, and how a Space Shuttle lands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m learning to better convey myself in the language I speak every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel more at ease reading a history book with a dictionary, and yet, one week later, I often can’t remember the names of those heroes and cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until a few months ago, I couldn’t tell a hyphen, an en dash, and an em dash apart.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m puzzled by a new foreign language—why there have to be more tenses than what seems necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is as if I were back to my childhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moving to a new country for graduate school means a lot more than pursing a degree or getting professional training. The elements of my days are different from what I was used to. I’m holding thoughts and attitudes I could never imagine. I’ve been encountering opinions that are the exact opposite of mine, yet closer to the truth. There are moments of exhilaration, as well as of unease and doubt—like what a child would experience in an exotic garden without their parents around.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m being taught to explore science as the way nature works, instead of merely as equations and models on paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been implanted in my mind that in research, integrity, clarity, and originality outweigh productivity and popularity, as they should always do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve realized that there are more dimensions in one’s education. Science &amp;amp; Engineering is merely one of them. Test preparation isn’t really one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I now believe that confidence and vigor are the cornerstones of all achievements, which can only be exhausted by fear and cynicism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m being shown that active communication is the expressway to pleasure, for ourselves and for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;. . .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The essence of childhood is neither innocence nor immaturity. It’s a unique period when a new world is unwrapped in front of us, in which we try, fail, learn, and reform ourselves. It’s less common that an adult has to go through it again. But I am willing to. To me, it’s more fun to watch how much one can change than how much one can achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kept a diary when I was a kid. Now it’s a good time to resume this habit.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 18 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
